

Valentyna Kuzmych

Front End Developer, Designer and Entrepreneur

Designer: UI/UX designer with a passion for designing beautiful and functional user experiences.

Programmer: Front End Developer who focuses on writing clean, reusable, elegant and efficient code.

Entrepreneur: started at least 5 companies (alone and with friends). Two of them were successful, one is on hold.

I \bigvee coffee and cooking.

Objective

To find a position of UI developer / Web Designer / Front End developer in a company where I can create significant websites/applications, make architectural decisions and take responsibility for them. I'm searching for the job which gives we ability to lead the software product from the scratch to end users, communicate directly with customers and stakeholders.

Work Experience

Dates	Work
2022 - current	Lead Specialist (Front End developer) in NACP National Agency on Corruption Prevention My role is developing new features and supporting web portals for NACP (https:// sanctions.nazk.gov.ua/, https:// vision.nazk.gov.ua/, https://study.nazk.gov.ua/, https://nazk.gov.ua/ and inner projects)
2015-2022	Senior UI developer in <u>EFG</u> private bank in Switzerland My role was dealing with all kind of UI issues - layouts, front-end, design, communication. Also I initiated and created EFG Design System v.1
2019-2022	Manager, designer, developer in own companies <u>Gandr.IO</u> , <u>Publaw Project</u>
2020	UI/UX designer and Front-end Developer in TeeVid French-Israel video conference startup Create designs and implement it (React)
2018	Web Developer in <u>Ricardo</u> The biggest online trade platform in Switzerland Create code for 'Ricardo Assistant tool'
2017	Developer in <u>Teacher Horizons</u> Service that brings schools and teachers together Migration of website from outdated stack to HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap/Angular
2016	Front-End developer in <u>AdPepper</u> German marketing company Creating tool for advertising audience targeting. HTML, CSS, JQuery, PHP

2015	Web-developer in ChartsNow.Mobi musical application from UK Creating web and mobile templates for corporate products HTML, CSS, JavaScript
till 2014	I worked mostly as a web developer or designer in outsourcing companies and web agencies - <u>Ciklum</u> , <u>Kuadriga</u> , <u>Livatek</u> , <u>Yellow Lab</u> , <u>Negeso</u> - or just like freelancer

Knowledge and Skills

Design stack:

Web site design	****
Web app design	****
Logo design	***
User interface	****
Mobile app design	***
User experience	***
Usability	****
Prototyping	***
Creating presentations	****
Creating UX prototypes	****

Design Tools:

Adobe Creative Suite	****
Figma	****
Keynotes	****
PowerPoint	****
InVision	****

Front End Stack:

CSS(3)	****
Bootstrap Framework (3,4)	****

JavaScript	***
LESS	****
HTML(5)	****
WordPress	****
Yii framework	***
SASS/SCSS	****
BEM metodology	****
AngularJS	***
Angular	***
React	***
00P	****
JSON	****
MySQL	***
TypeScript	***
XML	****
Builder Pattern	****
JQuery	***
svn/git/bower/npm/gulp	****

Web:

Cross browser attitude	****
Browser Performance	****
Adaptive/Responsive design	****
SEO/analytics	****
Google analytics	****
Semantics and standards	****

Classic programming:

Java	***
. NET	***
Objective C	**
Swift	***
Embedded C (IoT)	***
MySQL	***

Code Examples on Git

- <u>Cooking Book</u> HTML, CSS, Angular, TypeScript
- Real Estate Agency HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Query
- <u>DogPetPro</u> Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Responsive

Education

National University of Kyiv-Mohyla Academy:	Bachelor of Science (BS), Economics
Kyiv Academy of Media Arts:	Design and Visual Communications
Ukraine Information Institute:	Web Technology
English level:	Upper intermediate/B2

References



Pavlo Tkachuk

Senior Frontend Developer at N-iX

I've worked with Valentyna on the same project and team for almost 5 years at Ciklum and can recommend her as one of the most valuable team members. As a professional, she contributed a great deal to the UI/UX design and to the front end of the product. I admire her passion for work and her hardworking personality very much. She is a team player and a very friendly, open-minded person that would be a perfect fit for any team.

Kind regards,

Pasha



Olha Nosalska ·

UI/UX Designer at Ciklum

I had a wonderful experience working with such an amazing person and a talented developer. An excellent team player, open to discussion, focused on solving problems in the most optimal way, high expertise in Front End Engineering. Working with Valentyna you always feel support and friendliness. Incredibly happy for our cooperation.



Philippe Peron

CDO. Evolve, a partner in business and technology, our talented teams build great software, on time and on budget.

It's been a great professional experience to work with Valentyna over the last years.

She's got a very valuable experience and deep knowledge of Front-End technics.

Coupling this with her attention to detail and extreme rigor makes Valentyna a reliable contributor, able to implement almost any kind of Design without any surprises and communicate accordingly with stakeholders if any challenge appears.

I would strongly recommend Valentyna as a Senior Front-End Dev and UX/UI Designer.